Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/anvitabajpai (LinkedIn)

www.amazon.com/Anvita-Bajpai/e/B00Y0O4OZO (Portfolio) anvitabajpailoe.blogspot.in/ (Blog)

Top Skills

Product Management Machine Learning Software Engineering

Honors-Awards

Featured in ParentCircle Magazine
Turning Points of Uncommon People
– A Book of Revelations by Anvita
Bajpai

A coverage in PanIIT-USA newsletter

A coverage titled "Launch of TURNING POINTS book during a Kathak dance event" in Indian Express

A coverage titled "Learn ways to succeed from TURNING POINTS.." in Hindustan Daily

Publications

State of the art in Web Design and Content Creation for Indian Languages

Startup: Product Usability – Analysis

3D Printing: Just Because I Can, Should I?

Web Developmental Issues – A Case Study of GITASUPERSITE

Make It Happen

Patents

SYSTEM AND METHOD FOR COMPLAINTS ACQUISITION AND CLASSIFICATION

SYSTEM AND METHOD FOR PROVIDING ASSISTANCE FOR COOKING FOOD ITEMS IN REAL-TIME

Anvita Bajpai

Consulting Senior Director at Oracle

Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

Summary

During her 20+ years of professional journey with MNCs and Startups, Anvita has created value, managed teams & built GenAl, ML & Al-powered solutions across domains; and also published Research Papers, Patents, business & technology Articles, and three non-technology Books.

An awardee of 51 Fabulous Global Smart Cities Leaders 2020, and Women Influencer Innovator of the Year 2021, Anvita Bajpai is an alumna of IIT Madras and IIM Bangalore. Her last venture, SunvAI, is the recipient of GIPC Award 2020 for IP and Innovation.

Anvita has been an invited speaker at leading conferences such as Al Connect 2018, Global IP Convention 2019, India Electronics Week 2020, IPRG 2022, WIPF 2023 and recognized as Powerful Indian Women in IP 2021 by World IP Forum.

Experience

Oracle

4 years

Consulting Senior Director
January 2023 - Present (2 years 6 months)

Oracle Banking Consulting | Customer Centricity & Value Creation | GenAl & ML

Master Principal Cloud Architect

July 2021 - January 2023 (1 year 7 months)

Innovation | Customer Centricity | Thought Leadership | Academia/Startup Collaboration

Conference Speaking - ICISI 2021; Convergence 2021; Oracle ML Summit 2021 & 2022; IPRG 2022; ICCIIT 2022; DES 2022; WIPF 2023 (upcoming) |

SYSTEM AND METHOD FOR SEMANTIC ANALYSIS FOR IRRELEVANT SECTION DETECTION IN LEGAL DOCUMENTS

SYSTEM AND METHOD FOR COMPLAINTS GENUINENESS VERIFICATION IN A SMART CITY

SYSTEM AND METHOD FOR SEMANTIC ANALYSIS FOR CONTRADICTION DETECTION IN LEGAL AND OTHER DOCUMENTS Oracle Workshops - (i) Machine Learning Hands-On Lab @ Developer Day India; (ii) Techfest JAPAC

-

Organizational Responsibilities | Team Building | Mentorship & collaboration for design & development of processes, AI frameworks, patents and AI assets on Oracle Cloud:

- * Industry: Banking, Healthcare, Retail, Public Sector etc.
- * Technology: Enterprise Search using BERT | Large model training on GPU | NLP | OCI AI services, like, Speech, Vision, Language | Analytics (OAC) | ML & Data Sc. | Python | Microservices | Cloud Deployment

Member of Architecture Board, Center of Excellence, CE, JAPAC Member of D&I Board, Cloud Engineering, JAPAC

-

Mentor at Revv Up - Telangana Al Mission (T-AIM) powered by NASSCOM

-

Others/Volunteering - Virtual knowledge sharing sessions at various universities & colleges in India

SunvAl

Founder

August 2017 - June 2021 (3 years 11 months)

SunvAI - Recipient of the GIPC Award 2020 for Innovation and IP

Filing of 10 provisional patents | Pre-launch PoCs | Free beta version of India's 1st Al-powered Assistive Tool for Consumers (conforming to CPA 2019 | aligned with SDG#16) with multilingual (Hindi | हिंदी) features - using NLP, Python, Microservices Architecture, Cloud Deployment | 44 Invited Talks, Panel Discussions, Webinars & Articles; National & International Conference Participations; Media Coverages; Online Product Exhibitions

Founder's Accolades: 51 Fabulous Global Smart Cities Leaders 2020; Women Influencer Innovator of the Year 2021

https://www.amazon.com/Anvita-Bajpai/e/B00Y0O4OZO/Book Author 2012 - 2017 (5 years)

Hindustan Daily credited Anvita's second book as a guide to "Learn Ways to Succeed" in life.

- 1. Life, Odds & Ends (fiction, short-stories), 2014
- 2. Turning Points of Uncommon People (non-fiction, true stories), 2016
- 3. I Feel... I Think...: Pages from My Diary (non-fiction, a rich collection of articles), 2017

Anvita has interacted with a diverse set of people while conducting research & writing her books and given related talks at the Graduate Society for Women in Engineering at UIUC, IL, USA, World Book Fair 2014, Unilever's International Women's Day 2016 among others.

As a distinguished women in her field — writing, Anvita is awardee of the Golden Lotus from IIT Madras Alumni Association for International Women's Day 2017.

Wipro
Lead Consultant
October 2014 - April 2015 (7 months)
CTO Office, Bangalore

As part of Wipro's CTO office, handled pre-sales CXO interactions for defining "Future Ready" solutions; mentored team members; and demonstrated Thought Leadership through Public Speaking (at GIDS'15, and WIAD'15), Publishing Articles, and Patent Filing (in the IoT space)

Vimagino Solutions Pvt Ltd Domain Expert & Advisor July 2012 - July 2014 (2 years 1 month)

Algorithms and Domain Specific Features for Vimagino's Offering - Chat cum Recommendation Engine "vHelp" - along with presenting concepts to VCs etc. In 2013 Vimagino was selected for Microsoft's Accelerator Program, and got new customers like Yaatra.com

MyD (stealth-mode) Founder July 2009 - June 2012 (3 years)

& 2016 | Studied behavioural patterns to create human-centric products and solutions in times of IoT (Internet of Things) to explore solution for Social Profiling for Recommendation Engines

IIM Bangalore Guest Faculty

July 2009 - July 2009 (1 month)

Decidyn

Assistant Vice President

July 2008 - July 2009 (1 year 1 month)

- Strategy & Execution | Fund & Stakeholder Management
- Built & managed teams to design & develop desktop and web-based (SaaS) product-line for airline, banking and retail industry analytics solutions - using Support Vector Machines (SVM), .NET, C++, J2EE, Azure

Applied Research Group, Satyam

Software Architect

August 2007 - June 2008 (11 months)

Managed team to develop solutions for handing large scale multimedia data for targeting & personalization using Matlab, C++

-

Published conference research papers

Oracle

Application Engineer - IT

August 2004 - March 2007 (2 years 8 months)

Worked with Oracle Healthcare group in J2EE and related technologies | Handled 2nd most complex module of HTB | Wrote white paper for handling security module for healthcare product

IIT Kanpur

Research Engineer

July 1999 - July 2001 (2 years 1 month)

Worked in the area of Internet Technology and handling Indian language fonts for https://www.gitasupersite.iitk.ac.in/ using LAMP stack | Website hosting | Collaborated with C-DAC Pune for development of fonts | Presented my work at (i) STRANS-2001 and (ii) National level Workshop on Building Large Websites, 2000

Education

Indian Institute of Technology, Madras
MS (by research), Computer Science · (2001 - 2004)

Indian Institute of Management, Bangalore

Entrepreneurship · (2009 - 2009)

Oracle University

University Paris-Dauphine, Paris, France & IFIM Law School, Bangalore

International Certificate Course on "Legal and Institutional Framework of European Union Law" · (2019 - 2019)

IIT Kanpur

CERTIFICATE, Architecting Software for the Cloud · (2012 - 2013)